[{"id": "5fe9381f6bd93ce3a4e5f67e", "question": "Hippopotomonstrosesquipedaliophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long words", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caf3", "question": "What medical term is used to describe the process of sweating?", "answer": "Hydrosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64e", "question": "What must a mole do every four hours so it doesn't die?", "answer": "Eat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60160173fe83fe1f2a824c5f", "question": "According to a famous Polish legend, which creature made a blanket to keep baby Jesus warm?", "answer": "A spider, which is why Poles have a great reverence for spiders.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aae2", "question": "Khartoum is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd63", "question": "What Indonesian word names the art of successively waxing and dyeing fabric?", "answer": "Batik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab60", "question": "Prague is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a049", "question": "Who was the first man to appear on the cover of Playboy Magazine?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b943364247bf200fb88a", "question": "Who popularized the song \"A Boy Named Sue\" in 1969?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f5", "question": "Where are you if you land at Norman Manley airport?", "answer": "Kingston Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be03", "question": "What usually has cream in its \"New England\" version and tomatoes in its \"Manhattan\" version?", "answer": "Clam chowder", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be0", "question": "What popular singer had a chimpanzee name Scatter?", "answer": "Elvis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f31", "question": "In mythology, who defeated the serpent Apep every night in his solar barge?", "answer": "Ra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9a", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae43", "question": "How old was John F. Kennedy when he was assassinated?", "answer": "46", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1de", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does the term \"Omakase\" translate to in English?", "answer": "I'll leave it up to you", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f0", "question": "What company makes the Xbox console?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5971e1a689261e916c8e09b4", "question": "What were the Crusades?", "answer": " A series of religious wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76fa4eec85e375820b2ed", "question": "What is the largest city in Switzerland?", "answer": "Zurich", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d39", "question": "The co-creator of Superman, Joe Shuster, was born in which Canadian town?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f61", "question": "According to Dustin Hoffman in \"Rain Man\", what's the only airline that has never had a crash?", "answer": "Qantas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8e", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Cathy Moriarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c1a49076251badbeacd", "question": "Which First Lady was the first born outside of America?", "answer": "Louisa Adams, the wife of John Quincy Adams, was born in London.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f7464a9e54d890926f6f6", "question": "How many steps must visitors take to reach the site of two Buddhist temples in China called Fanjingshan?", "answer": "8,888", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133941e", "question": "Which former member of the Beatles recorded albums with the Plastic Ono Band?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9fb", "question": "Marbella is a resort on which SpanIsh coast?", "answer": "Costa del Sol", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ea0b06d333868d34d759", "question": "After the bombing of Pearl Harbor which brand of potato chips changed its name to Jays?", "answer": "Japps potato chips", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d06d21a1c922dd1ac64b0", "question": "What is the oldest bridge over the river Seine in Paris?", "answer": "Pont Neuf", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddaa36ce05a3942286d88", "question": "Where in Mexico does Andy say he dreams of living in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Andy confides in Red that his dream place to live in is Zihuatanejo.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c3", "question": "What late 19\u00ad60's pop singer was backed by a group called the Union Gap?", "answer": "Gary Puckett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca26", "question": "Syncope is the medical name for what condition?", "answer": "Fainting", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596761c52b59efe0e9417ea5", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c14e", "question": "Porphyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "The color purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9b5608b8581f80b092c4", "question": "Which key button did Apple remove in its flagship iPhone X model?", "answer": "The Home button", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c0cb877e98cb9777896f", "question": "What Canadian province boasts the longest freshwater beach in the world?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af258c7b63e5727cf5a4848", "question": "Who co-produced the song \"Summertime\" with Will Smith?", "answer": "DJ Jazzy Jeff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597742ee284458f1d7854423", "question": "What \"America's Got Talent\" host replaced Nick Cannon?", "answer": "Tyra Banks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339695", "question": "Who starred as Achilles in the 2004 movie \"Troy\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51aa5ff04d658268c9307", "question": "Odysseus was the king of what island in the Mediterranean Sea?", "answer": "Ithaca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac8", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Montana?", "answer": "Helena", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f2186682715b82711ce7", "question": "Feijoada, the national dish of Brazil, originates from which country?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad49", "question": "In 1978, what terrorist group kidnapped and murdered former Italian prime minister Aldo Moro?", "answer": "Red Brigade", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a6d", "question": "All members of the \"Jackson 5\" were born in which US city?", "answer": "Gary, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d0", "question": "What is the only mammal with four knees?", "answer": "The Elephant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c153", "question": "A plague is a group of what insect?", "answer": "Locust", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049ec7cf93664eb10486b5", "question": "Dogteeth tetras are a family of freshwater fishes native to what continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59049990cf93664eb1048693", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0de59fcbed638185eaa15", "question": "Which U.S. state has the longest width east to west?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7856ff048f679a45abd8", "question": "What openings in a leaf allow gas exchange?", "answer": "Stomata", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d80", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Matthew Harrison Brady in the novel \"Inherit the Wind\"?", "answer": "William Jennings Bryan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b6f", "question": "Who wrote the novel series \"The Green Mile\"?", "answer": "Stephen King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e4", "question": "How much did the first Amazon Kindle device cost?", "answer": "$399", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1f", "question": "What place did Dante describe as having \"Abandon hope, all ye who enter here\" written over its doors?", "answer": "Hell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5e5e6ce05a3942286e32", "question": "Who won the 2009 Sporting News Major League Player of the Year award?", "answer": "Albert Pujols", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c163", "question": "What airport has the code MME?", "answer": "Durham Tees Valley", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be8", "question": "The TV show \"Seinfeld\" is a show about what?", "answer": "Nothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6f75a9e54d890926f6d1", "question": "What was the capital of Michigan before Lansing?", "answer": "Detroit -- Due to Detroit's proximity to Canada, a perceived threat at the time, Lansing became the state's capital in 1847.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a1b620565ad31a57c7a5", "question": "What was the first US state to have two female senators at the same time?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c88efbde8045e48466dc", "question": "What are animals with backbones called?", "answer": "Vertebrate", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b32324fbf195a31e15d738f", "question": "Which novel did George Eliot publish in 1876?", "answer": "Daniel Deronda", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea41a9ff048f679a45ab70", "question": "What is the chemical term for a peptide; two amino acids linked together?", "answer": "An Amide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c420", "question": "How many moons does Mars have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecb", "question": "What French word for \"jewel\" became a common name for American movie houses?", "answer": "Bijou", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be15", "question": "What instrument do Australian Aborigines traditionally make from termite-hollowed eucalyptus trees?", "answer": "The didgeridoo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a552", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339351", "question": "What was Ray's occupation on the TV show \"Everybody Loves Raymond\"?", "answer": "Sports writer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d077c9870e6f05ba600867", "question": "What film starred Drew Barrymore, Mary-Louise Parker, and Matthew McConaughey?", "answer": "Boys on the Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e190e748bb36357acdf5", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Murder on the Orient Express\"?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af46", "question": "Who was the famous teacher of Socrates?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb2917e83c707845b2113", "question": "Which scientist established the ROYGBIV color spectrum?", "answer": "Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945c", "question": "In the movie \"Casablanca\", what number does Rick tell the Bulgarian to bet on?", "answer": "22", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339887", "question": "What colour did The Hulk originally start as?", "answer": "Grey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f7", "question": "Who was the first Toronto Blue Jay player to lead the American league in home runs?", "answer": "Jesse Barfield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62e", "question": "The Roadrunner is the official bird of which US state?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b809", "question": "Who are the Mario Brothers usually trying to save?", "answer": "Princess Peach", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a54b20565ad31a57c7c9", "question": "In the first televised baseball game, the Cincinnati Reds played what team?", "answer": "Brooklyn Dodgers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65b", "question": "Upon his death, what convicted killer donated his corneas?", "answer": "Gary Gilmore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7e7b2b24f84e0b9f9ffbc", "question": "How many states comprise Australia?", "answer": "Six", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1c", "question": "What classic sitcom character was played by Irene Ryan from 1962 to 1971?", "answer": "Granny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab0c04baab681b09292167", "question": "What 2005 horror short film shares a name with a piece of jewelry?", "answer": "Rings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac73", "question": "The Bronze Age was characterized by the use of which malleable metal and one of its alloys?", "answer": "Copper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72d1aad0874f1a5e2d1c2c", "question": "What band has the most No. 1 hits on \"The Billboard Hot 100\" with 20 songs to reach No. 1?", "answer": "The Beatles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3a", "question": "In the song \"Zip-a-Dee-Doo-Dah\", what kind of animal sits on Uncle Remus' shoulder?", "answer": "A bluebird", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7decff048f679a45ac02", "question": "Aphenphosmphobia is fear of what?", "answer": "Being touched", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60121b0b63c99d48cd169b0a", "question": "The word \"susurrus\" is an example of which literary device?", "answer": "Onomatopoeia -- Some words sound just like their meanings.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bf", "question": "What does Marilyn Monroe say are a \"girl's best friend\" in Gentlemen Prefer Blondes?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da5", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Gradgrind?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891a", "question": "What Italian city was Michelangelo raised in?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b090", "question": "In 1983, the first Disney theme park built outside the US opened in what country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59049c21cf93664eb10486a5", "question": "In which North American city would you find Joe Shuster Way?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a915", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Wayne?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6c", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Daredevil\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb7", "question": "Portia Simpson-Miller was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338be4", "question": "What is the name of the controversial novel that was written by Salmon Rushdie?", "answer": "The Satanic Verses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339721", "question": "Who was the main actor in the movie \"A Beautiful Mind\"?", "answer": "Russell Crowe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9e209e748bb36357acdf8", "question": "What was Alfred Hitchcock\u2019s first American made film?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b103", "question": "What infamous gangster was betrayed by \"the lady in red\"?", "answer": "John Dillinger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c71d", "question": "What is a tanager?", "answer": "A bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010c5370775fa611bce67c4", "question": "What newspaper is nicknamed \"the Gray Lady\"?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81fb7d0de9af39e9d4698", "question": "What state had the first paved road in the U.S.?", "answer": "Michigan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396a7", "question": "What two actors exchanged faces in the 1997 movie \"Face/Off\"?", "answer": "Nicholas Cage and John Travolta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173e3544491cbd7c5a17ae", "question": "According to U.S. history, which is the \"date which will live in infamy\"?", "answer": "Dec. 7, 1941 -- The date the U.S. naval base, Pearl Harbor, was the target of a devastating surprise attack by Japanese forces.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f79", "question": "What was Marky Mark's backing band?", "answer": "The Funky Bunch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f03", "question": "What author created the character of Mike Hammer?", "answer": "Mickey Spillane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f4d68af848b908361b881", "question": "What was the number of Twitter\u2019s original character limit?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ef2108d98002fdd633de", "question": "When is the only time a flag should be flown upside down?", "answer": "Emergency", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17f", "question": "Who succeeded Pierre Trudeau as the 16th Prime Minister of Canada?", "answer": "Joe Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59a", "question": "Which major car company owns the luxury automotive brand Lexus?", "answer": "Toyota", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe7", "question": "What is the name of Stephen Hawking's cosmology book published In 1988?", "answer": "A Brief History Of Time", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec87cfec223966ae8f8818", "question": "Which 1980's NBA player set the record for most assists by a player during his rookie season?", "answer": "Mark Jackson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec881aec223966ae8f881b", "question": "Blondie of the film \"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly\" is also known by what name?", "answer": "\"the Man with No Name\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d564877e98cb97778a64", "question": "What actor played the school principal in E.T., only to have his scene cut when Spielberg decided that his presence would be too distracting?", "answer": "Harrison Ford", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a61", "question": "Whose wife could eat no lean?", "answer": "Jack Sprat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f6cf01dd7bf43be5e834", "question": "What is throwing three rocks in a game of Rock, Paper, Scissors called?", "answer": "Avalanche", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e96438e4e5d4832e6310", "question": "In what years did the Mariposa War go on?", "answer": "1850 through 1851", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b88521d8c1817608d53f1", "question": "Roquefort, Feta and Manchego are all cheeses made from the milk of which animal?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cc", "question": "What is the northernmost Scandinavian country?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d9e", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Swift?", "answer": "Victor Appleton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febbc557e83c707845b214b", "question": "Which NFL player later went on to become a US Supreme Court Judge?", "answer": "Byron White who was a runner-up to the Heisman Trophy in 1937, served as an Associate Supreme Court Justice from 1962 to 1993.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133965e", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", Mr. Burns sells the power plant to businessmen from what country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e7", "question": "Which film mogul was famous for illogical sayings such as \"include me out\"?", "answer": "Sam Goldwyn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afd6", "question": "What horse race was first held in 1875 at the Churchill Downs racetrack?", "answer": "Kentucky Derby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd73", "question": "What organization grew out of the Hubbard Dianetic Research Foundation?", "answer": "The Church of Scientology", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399bf", "question": "What was Captain Stubing's first name, on the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Merrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338edf", "question": "What famous name in opera was the son-in-law of composer Franz Liszt?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdab8370b8cce1e6fda7050", "question": "In the legal world, what does GATT stand for?", "answer": "General Agreement on Trade and Tariffs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a686", "question": "Which three states share a border with Michigan?", "answer": "Indiana, Ohio and Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ff", "question": "Who stars as Rick Santoro in the 1998 movie \"Snake Eyes\"?", "answer": "Nicholas Cage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be93", "question": "What company opened its first Italian eatery at Brooklyn's Kings Plaza Shopping Center in 1967?", "answer": "Sbarro", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ea43b24f84e0b9f9ffd2", "question": "What is a figure with eight equal sides called?", "answer": "Regular Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a64c", "question": "Which US state is home to Arches National Park?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb69", "question": "What tennis player was named \"Sexiest Woman in the World\" by FHM magazine in 2002?", "answer": "Anna Kournikova", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339430", "question": "What comedic duo of the 1920s and 1930s were real-life best friends?", "answer": "Laurel & Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e2", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of the Springfield football team?", "answer": "The Atoms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a8", "question": "The World's first \"sister cities\" were what Spanish city and its US midwestern namesake?", "answer": "Toledo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac03", "question": "The Plains of Abraham are located in which North American country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c59c", "question": "What is a male beaver called?", "answer": "A buck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baa2", "question": "According to the Scoville scale of heat, what the hottest naturally occurring chemical?", "answer": "Resiniferatoxin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6606aa5bfecdd737e0833", "question": "In which state are two-thirds of all Fortune 500 companies headquartered?", "answer": "Delaware", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad4d", "question": "In which country do parts of Hadrian's Wall still remain?", "answer": "Great Britain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4dd8306d333868d34d703", "question": "Eric the Red was a Viking from what period of time?", "answer": "900s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb659c5dad637d903c8835", "question": "Queen Alexandra's father and brother were kings of what country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebf", "question": "Sepp Blatter and Jack Warner are former executives from which international sports organization?", "answer": "FIFA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e27", "question": "What began as a ligature of the letters \"e\" and \"t\"?", "answer": "The ampersand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e2fd06d333868d34d72b", "question": "Which conflict ended with the \"Good Friday Agreement\"?", "answer": "The Troubles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8fb", "question": "The Bitterroot Range of the Rockies is located on the border between what two US states?", "answer": "Idaho and Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f9", "question": "What is the second smallest country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339873", "question": "In Disney's \"Alice in Wonderland\", who is the companion of The Walrus?", "answer": "A Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b630", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"C\" referred to as?", "answer": "Charlie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121cdd63c99d48cd169b19", "question": "What do the iron bars of the \"Nelson Mandela\" sculpture represent?", "answer": "Imprisonment -- Created by Marco Cianfanelli, it is located at the same spot of his arrest on R102 highway in South Africa.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab5", "question": "Who wrote, Papa's Angels: A Christmas Story in 1996?", "answer": "Collin Wilcox Paxton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397ca", "question": "Who sang the 1956 song \"Ape Call\"?", "answer": "Nervous Norvus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6bb", "question": "What river is located along the southern border of Texas?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b893", "question": "Who was the last tennis player to win a Grand Slam using a wooden racquet?", "answer": "Bjorn Borg", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa73", "question": "What US State flag has a Union Jack Flag on it?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4ae", "question": "How many sides does a rhombus have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afff", "question": "What was President \"Teddy\" Roosevelt's real first name?", "answer": "Theodore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b5", "question": "What did A.J. stand for on the TV show \"Simon & Simon\"?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339778", "question": "What secluded retreat does Karen White head for in The Howling?", "answer": "The Colony", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ff", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a990", "question": "What city named its airport after Galileo Galilei?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173aa044491cbd7c5a179a", "question": "What prominent African-American abolitionist helped slaves escape to freedom via the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman -- She made thirteen dangerous missions to help about 70 enslaved people reach freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928b", "question": "\"Highlander\" tells the story of which immortal swords-man?", "answer": "Connor MacLeod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60062a6ec9d816e292245c18", "question": "What Jewish German-born American sculptor helped usher in the postminimal art movement in the 1960s?", "answer": "Eva Hesse (She is known for her pioneering work in materials such as latex, fiberglass, and plastics.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbb", "question": "In Roman mythology who killed Remus?", "answer": "Romulus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b370", "question": "What was Ghandi's profession?", "answer": "Lawyer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cea", "question": "Who wrote \"The Scarlett Letter\"?", "answer": "Nathaniel Hawthorne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b3", "question": "What was boxer John L. Sullivan nicknamed?", "answer": "The Boston Strong Boy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13f", "question": "How many months did it take the Mayflower to cross the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "2", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbe", "question": "What name was given to the leather protection cowboys wore over the front of their pants?", "answer": "Chaps", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2be", "question": "The first atomic bomb test split an atom of what fissionable element?", "answer": "Plutonium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff14563b0ee8c595b6d39b9", "question": "What play's full title includes \"A Trivial Comedy for Serious People\"?", "answer": "\"The Importance of Being Earnest\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339356", "question": "What actor played The Riddler in the original \"Batman\" TV series?", "answer": "Frank Gorshin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0de", "question": "Where exactly were the \"Bee Gees\" band members actually born?", "answer": "The Isle Of Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c341", "question": "How many ventricles does the brain have?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3b", "question": "Who shocked the public with his 1863 painting \"Luncheon on the Grass\"?", "answer": "\u00c9douard Manet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ea37b24f84e0b9f9ffd1", "question": "An Octagon with equal sides is called a what?", "answer": "A Regular Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6aa2420565ad31a57c811", "question": "Who became the vice president after Spiro T. Agnew resigned?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ab", "question": "What 1972 movie revolves around the happenings at the Kit-Kat Klub?", "answer": "Cabaret", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e09", "question": "What New York banker did Star Jones marry in 2004?", "answer": "Al Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523f9b736d4be723796b59", "question": "What distiller and entrepreneur founded the town of Walkerville, which is now a heritage neighborhood of Windsor, Ontario in Canada?", "answer": "Hiram Walker", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59071cb03745b36be73039cf", "question": "In what present-day country was the first space launch facility located?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600cc6d76de0eb824d4052f9", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest living tree canopy, the size of three soccer fields?", "answer": "India -- A 550-year-old ficus benghalensis tree there, known as Thimmamma Marrimanu, has combined crowns that span 5.41 acres.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e95237ccba3ffe45786dc", "question": "Who sang the theme song for the TV show \"The Love Boat\"?", "answer": "Jack Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c81", "question": "What famous American author published Ulysses S. Grant's \"Personal Memoirs\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af02", "question": "The Continental Army captured Ford Ticonderoga during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7348beec85e375820b237", "question": "Where was the first lighthouse built?", "answer": "Alexandria, Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae57", "question": "Which US president was once a peanut farmer?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e98", "question": "What movie did the villain Mrs. Danvers appear in?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b008", "question": "What city in Idaho was the first in the world to use electricity generated by nuclear power?", "answer": "Arco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338992", "question": "How old is the teenage lead character at the end of the book \"Anne of Green Gables\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baae", "question": "What company helped the US Army Corps of Engineers develop the \"walkie-talkie\" in the early 1930\u2019s?", "answer": "Motorola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d35", "question": "What English town was William Shakespeare born in?", "answer": "Stratford-upon-Avon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391aa", "question": "Who played James Bond in the 1971 film \"Diamonds Are Forever\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b56", "question": "In which decade was the first issue of \"The New Yorker\" published?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cdc83e347d002c297e4e8", "question": "In 1973 Roland Ohisson was buried in a coffin made of what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b6a0e662d71a5365100a", "question": "The book \"20,000 Leagues Under the Sea\" was written by whom?", "answer": "Jules Verne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a4", "question": "Mt. Blanc is the highest peak in what mountain range?", "answer": "The Alps", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c703", "question": "What famous 19th-century American writer was issued a patent for adjustable elastic suspenders?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad6", "question": "Dustin Hoffman earned his first Oscar nomination for what movie?", "answer": "The Graduate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2cfb42596a59cbdfbd372", "question": "Who said, \u201cStrong minds discuss ideas, average minds discuss events, weak minds discuss people\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5906830bff9c0647b50a80a3", "question": "Which actress, portraying an Alderaan princess, passed away in December, 2016?", "answer": "Carrie Fisher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af81", "question": "What was Paul Revere's profession?", "answer": "Silversmith", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7abb856490a8cc1a6e5297", "question": "What are the six types of quarks more generally referred to as?", "answer": "Flavors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b657", "question": "What company introduced the first radio with push-button tuning in 1927?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c84", "question": "Who wrote the play \"A Streetcar Named Desire\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcda", "question": "What did Coleco name its 1983 home computer?", "answer": "Adam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a2e", "question": "What Chaucer collection of stories was sold by a group of pilgrims on their way to a shrine?", "answer": "Canterbury Tales", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b5a101dd7bf43be5e7d3", "question": "What is the term for the space between your eyebrows?", "answer": "Glabella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe12d0de39efa6330e0fec9", "question": "How long is the Panama Canal?", "answer": "51 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51cecff04d658268c931f", "question": "What famous general was once attacked by rabbits?", "answer": "Napoleon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6fb", "question": "Annapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a967", "question": "What Briton with an American wife was the governor of the Bahamas during World War II?", "answer": "King Edward VIII", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60136f851381754895396377", "question": "What superhero uses a device called \"The Cosmic Treadmill\"?", "answer": "Flash -- The Cosmic Treadmill is used to help the Flash amplify his already considerable powers.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac89", "question": "How were Theodore and Franklin Roosevelt related?", "answer": "They were fifth cousins", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae29", "question": "In which decade did Winston Churchill win the Nobel prize for literature?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a340", "question": "Who played The Monster in the 1931 film \"Frankstein\"?", "answer": "Boris Karloff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5989ab04cb8751d53e7d7606", "question": "Who follows Godel and Escher in the title of a 1979 book by Douglas Hofstadter?", "answer": "Bach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddf", "question": "What kind of wine accompanies Hannibal Lecter's liver and fava bean dinner?", "answer": "Chianti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69af420565ad31a57c758", "question": "What famous inventor proposed to his wife in Morse Code?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac07", "question": "In which continent would you find the Congo River?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a553613e1c6f9840ba31a4", "question": "Who won the 1990 Nobel Peace Prize?", "answer": "Mikhail Gorbachev", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dffa09616e6c6d4eba4fe", "question": "Which US Holiday is celebrated on October 12th?", "answer": "Columbus Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ed0d06d333868d34d769", "question": "What toy was originally created as a dog\u2019s chew toy?", "answer": "Rubber Duck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefc3536ce05a3942286f22", "question": "What is the name of Jack Nicholson's character in the film, \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "J.J \"Jake\" Gittes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76840eec85e375820b29e", "question": "Which U.S. city is referred to as \"The Hub of the Universe\"?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe658adae7e414034b5aef5", "question": "Which battle was fought on August 22, 1485?", "answer": "Battle of Bosworth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f6", "question": "What Italian scientist discovered methane and invented the first battery?", "answer": "Alessandro Volta", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071ec93745b36be73039e5", "question": "In the \"Revival\" comic book series, what is the family name of the brothers who try to sell parts of the revivers?", "answer": "Check", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2fb", "question": "Who has held the world record in the pole vault, 6.14 m, for more than twenty years?", "answer": "Sergei Bubka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523d2a736d4be723796b3e", "question": "Musician Drake first gained popularity appearing on which teen TV show?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339669", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96bd7ccba3ffe45786f1", "question": "How many countries border the Black Sea?", "answer": "Six", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bb", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\", what is Juliet's surname?", "answer": "Capulet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975c", "question": "Helen Mirren won best actress Oscar, beating out Meryl Streep, for which 2006 movie?", "answer": "The Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b9", "question": "Who took the role of Lysander in the Disney version of \"A Midsummer Night's Dream\"?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2fb", "question": "In which 1966 film did Stephen Boyd star alongside Raquel Welch?", "answer": "Fantastic Voyage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f54", "question": "What was the name of Bilbo and Frodo Baggins' hobbit hole?", "answer": "Bag End", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c011", "question": "Sakhmet was the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War and healing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fceda4edfd43a087adc5", "question": "What number is represented by \"C\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "100", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe2578c658e585fda9cfa3d", "question": "What is the ability to shift from two-wheel drive to four-wheel drive while the vehicle is moving called?", "answer": "Shift-On-The-Fly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65c171f3c0ead6880d60d", "question": "What did the Russian people do with Vladimir Lenin's body after his death in 1924?", "answer": "Displayed it publicly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9af", "question": "Which substance has the chemical formula HCl?", "answer": "Hydrochloric acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad2", "question": "Althea Gibson was a pioneering African-American athlete in what sport?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b900", "question": "What sport uses clowns to protect the competitors?", "answer": "Rodeo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdd5d0a0499cffc60b84230", "question": "Who led the Solidarity movement and became President of Poland in 1990?", "answer": "Lech Walesa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be87", "question": "What type of a tree killed Albert Camus?", "answer": "Plane tree", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca59", "question": "A light aircraft without an engine is called a what?", "answer": "Glider or a sailplane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970f", "question": "In which decade did John Travolta star in \"Grease\"?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c553", "question": "What is studied by nephrology?", "answer": "Kidneys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a810", "question": "Zagreb is the capital of what European country?", "answer": "Croatia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c9", "question": "What was Audrey Hepburn's real last name?", "answer": "Ruston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3d9", "question": "What type of natural perfume comes from beavers?", "answer": "Castor", "category": "science"}]